okay so let's solve a limit this is the
limit as X approaches 69 of 6X squared
minus 408x minus 414 over x minus 69.
since we want to know the limit as X
approaches 69 we just substitute 69 in
for each of these x's and we can see
what we get so after you plug it into a
calculator all this on top gives us 0
and 69 minus 69 is also zero so this is
an indeterminate form we don't actually
know what number this is so we have to
find a different way to solve this so
let's try to simplify the stuff inside
the parentheses another way you can
think of a fraction is as a division
problem we're going to take this and
we're going to divide by x minus 69.
we're going to do some long division and
this is called polynomial long division
first step we want to know how many
times does X go into 6X squared well
it'll go in 6X times and that's because
6X times x gives us 6X squared and then
we also want to do 6X times the negative
69 which gives us negative 414x now
after we multiply this we want to
subtract these and this negative is
going to distribute both to the negative
6X and it's going to make the 414x
positive 6X squared minus 6X squared
cancel each other out and negative 408x
plus 414x is 6X and now that we're done
subtracting we can bring down the
negative 4 14. now we want to ask
ourselves how many times does X go into
6X well that's going to be 6 times and
that's because 6 times x equals 6X and
we also want to do 6 times negative 69
which is negative 414. and now we want
to subtract this from this well this
negative will distribute to both terms
making the first one negative and the
second one positive these cancel and
these cancel so we're just left with
zero so the answer to this divided by
this is 6X plus 6. so we can change this
whole thing into 6X plus 6. let's smush
this all together and now we're ready to
apply the limit so we want to know what
is this inside thing equal to when X
approaches 69 or we can plug in 69 for
the X at 6 times 69 is 414 so we have
414 plus 6 and that's equal to 420. so
the limit as X approaches 69 of this
right here is is equal to 420. now let's
put a box around it how exciting